WILLIAM DUPONT

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Belfast, United Kingdom | +44 7306 584317 | williamd.contact@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/williamdupont

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a dedicated, organized, and diligent software engineer with over 1 year of experience. Specialised in mobile software development, I have worked on both native and cross-platform systems.

I am experienced in the complete software lifecycle and have often played a key role at its different stages: meeting with key stakeholders, identifying project requirements and specifications, designing and prototyping, contributing to the production and delivery of software, bug fixing, testing.

I seek to apply and expand my knowledge and skills towards working in a collaborative environment to develop quality software solutions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

MOBILE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sentireal | Belfast, United Kingdom | Oct 2021 - Sep 2022

Sentireal is a start-up company developing bespoke software systems aimed at enhancing learning outcomes via the use of Augmented Reality and Virtual Reality technologies. As a mobile software engineer for Sentireal, I was tasked not only with technical work but also client facing challenges. As such, some of my key responsibilities included:

- Meeting with key clients to identify project requirements and specifications
- Designing and prototyping a bespoke software solution with Figma to ensure good user experience
- · Writing epics and user stories for the projects I was assigned to using Atlassian's Jira, following agile principles
- · Architecting and developing the agreed upon prototype from the ground up using appropriate state management solutions
- Use of Flutter for the development of cross-platform applications, Swift and the SwiftUI framework for native iOS applications
- Use of the MVVM and MVC design patterns in order to decouple business logic code from UI code
- Testing and bug fixing the developed software
- Use of appropriate version control techniques with Git
- Use of AWS for backend needs such as Cognito for authentication, DynamoDB for data persistence and exposure to Lambda

FRENCH TEACHERASSISTANT

Academie Lafayette | Kansas City, Missouri, USA | Jul 2017 - Jun 2018

The Academie Lafayette is a French immersion primary school located in the Missourian part of Kansas City, USA. As an assistant, I was teaching and helping my senior teach our native language to American children in kindergarten. Some of my responsibilities included:

- Preparing classrooms and class modules in French, as well as planning course of action
- Tailoring lessons to students needs as well as preparing private lessons for students that would stay after school hours
- Teaching literature to older students at high school level twice a month

EDUCATION

MSc Software Development

Queen's University Belfast | Belfast, United Kingdom | 2020 - 2021

Masters 1 of English History, Linguistics & Arts

Paris Diderot University | Paris, France | 2018 - 2019

Bachelor's Degree of English History, Linguistics & Arts

Paris-Est Gustave Eiffel University | Paris, France | 2014 - 2017

SKILLS

- Swift, SwiftUI
- AWS Cognito, DynamoDB
- SQL, NoSQL database

- Flutter, Dart
- Jira, Confluence
- Exposure to React, TypeScript
- Figma
- GitHub, Bitbucket
- Mobile & web development